Guide to the Proteus Ship's logs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Proteus Ship's logs
1969-1972
SC0603
Proteus.
1 Linear feet
These logs cover only the ship's operations, not the research work done by the scientists on board. Trip locations include the Mexican coast, Hawaii, Pacific Northwest coast from Oregon to British Columbia, and the Monterey Bay waters, as well as repair time in dry dock.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer from Hopkins Marine Station, 2001.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Proteus was a 100-foot tuna clipper acquired by the Hopkins Marine Station in 1968 and refitted as a research vessel. It was used from 1969 to 1972.
Description of the Collection
These logs cover only the ship's operations, not the research work done by the scientists on board. Trip locations include the Mexican coast, Hawaii, Pacific Northwest coast from Oregon to British Columbia, and the Monterey Bay waters, as well as repair time in dry dock.
Access Terms
Hopkins Marine Station; Proteus.; Wible, Joe; Marine biology research vessels.; Research vessels--United States.
Collection Contents
- Logs
  - along Mexican coast (rough log), June 1, 1969-July 21, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - along Mexican coast (smooth log), June 1, 1969-July 21, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - along Mexican coast (rough log), July 22, 1969-Sept. 12, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - along Mexican coast (smooth log), July 19, 1969-Sept. 8, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Monterey Bay operations, Sept. 15, 1969-Nov. 13, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - at Pacific Dry Dock in Oakland, Nov. 14, 1969-Dec. 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - at Pacific Dry Dock in Oakland, Jan. 1, 1970-Feb. 25, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Monterey Bay operations, Feb. 25, 1970-Apr. 24, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - to San Diego and Monterey Bay operations, Apr. 25, 1970-June 14, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Monterey Bay operations, June 15, 1970-Aug. 13, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Oregon to British Columbia, Aug. 14, 1970-Oct. 26, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Monterey Bay operations, Oct. 27, 1970-Jan. 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Monterey Bay operations, Feb. 1, 1971-June 3, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Monterey Bay operations, June 5, 1971-July 16, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hawaiian trip, July 17, 1971-Sept. 23, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Monterey Bay operations, Sept. 29, 1971-Mar. 6, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Monterey Bay operations and cruise south to Mexico (July 25-29), Mar. 7, 1972-July 27, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)